In this notebook, you'll be exploring job satisfaction according to the survey results.
在这次 Notebook 中 我们来探索调查问卷中工作满意度的情况
You'll notice that this was a little bit more open
你会发现这次 Notebook 中的问题
ended than some of the past notebooks that you worked through.
要比之前练习的问题开放性更高
And so, a place to start might just be to look at the first two questions and
一开始先来看两个问题
then work with the open cells above to answer the questions that you'll find below.
然后在上面几个空单元格里编写代码进行解答
So, the first question down here is just,
第一个问题是
what is the proportion of missing values in the job satisfaction column?
工作满意度这一列中缺失值的占比是多少
So, I'm just going to pull in the job satisfaction and let's see.
选出 JobSatisfaction 这一列
So, the proportion of missing value, is actually isnull.
用 isnull 来查看缺失值的情况
I think, we can do something like isnull, and this will give us trues and falses.
它会返回一些 True 和 False
And then, we can take a mean of a bunch of true and false values.
之后可以对这些 True/False 求均值
So, cool.
就可以看到
So, the proportion of missing value should be 0.2.
缺失值的比例为 0.2
This should be 0.2014.
这里应该是 0.2014
I wonder, I bet you that's not even going to give me,
之前的值是不对的
it should be 0.2014.
应该是 0.2014
And then, it says to give the letter, so l'm just going to do B.
在这里 我们需要给出字母选项 那应该是 b
It should be 0.2014.
是 0.2014
And then, according to the employment status,
下一个问题 对不同的工作状态 (EmploymentStatus)
which group has the highest average job satisfaction?
哪一类人群具有最高的工作满意度
So, we want to look at employment status
我们要先看一下有哪些工作状态
and I'm just going to do count_values or value_counts.
用 value_counts 方法
So, you can see that there are basically these different groups and they want,
可以看到有不同的类别
according to the employment status,
问题是 对于不同的工作状态
which group has the highest average job satisfaction?
哪个类别的工作满意度最高呢？
So, I'm going to do a groupby and I'm going to groupby the Employment Status.
我现在要使用 groupby 对 EmploymentStatus 列进行聚合
So, in the groupby function you can,
groupby 函数
I guess, it's a method because it lives on the data frame,
更准确地说应该是 DataFrame 的一个方法
but you can pass either a string with the column name or a list
你可以向 groupby 传入列名字符串或者是包含列名字符串的列表
And then, we can say,
然后 我们可以要求
"Give us the mean."
返回每个聚合组的均值
And we care about job satisfaction, great.
我们主要想看工作满意度
So, according to the employment status,
所以 根据不同的工作状态
which group has the highest job satisfaction?
哪一类人群的工作满意度最高呢?
We can see it's this independent contractor and we have a bunch of NaNs as well.
可以看到是自由工作者 还有很多没有数值的
So, looks like this should be D, cool.
看来这里的值应该是 d
And then in general,
下一个问题
do smaller companies appear to have employees with higher job satisfaction?
小型公司的成员通常会有更高的工作满意度吗?
So, I imagine there's something associated with the size of,
我猜这是某个跟规模有关、跟公司有关的特征
oh, company size, right there.
对的 CompanySize 就是这个
Cool. So hopefully, it just shows up because otherwise,
希望是对的
we'll have to dig through the whole list.
否则还要继续在全部列名中寻找其他特征
And let's do the same thing.
跟之前一样的代码
So, we'll do a groupby.
使用 groupby 对 CompanySize 进行聚合
I'll just take the mean and get the job satisfaction.
使用 mean 方法 选择 JobSatisfaction 列
So, this will give me the mean job satisfaction for each company size.
返回了每种规模公司的平均工作满意度
And I believe we can do like a sort values on this.
还可以使用 sort_values 这个函数
So, it looks like the highest said,
得分最高的人群
they prefer not to answer.
不想透露公司规模的信息
So, in general, do smaller companies appear to have employees with higher?
"总的来说 小型公司的工作满意度较高" 是对的吗?
So, these people I don't know,
这些人说不知道
these prefer not to answer.
这些人不想回答
But then, 10 to 19,
之后是 10 - 19 雇员的规模
the biggest companies have the lowest,
最大型的公司 工作满意度最小
and then the second biggest have the second lowest,
规模第二大的 满意度倒数第二
the third biggest have the third lowest,
规模第三大的 满意度倒数第三
then there's like middle sized companies and these are like super small company.
然后是中型公司 以及非常小的公司
This is a super small company.
这个是超级小型的公司
But in general, these companies here are,
但是总的来看 这些公司
so the one, two, three, four, five,
这五个类别的员工
these five are all smaller than these three.
比前面三个类别的员工满意度更高
So, in general, it kind of looks like that's the case.
所以总体上来看 的确是这样的
It's a little hard to tell but I would say,
虽然不是特别直观
there's probably enough information to say these three are the biggest and they
但是仍有足够的信息 这 3 个绝对是大型公司
have lower job satisfaction than these five-ish that are the smallest.
而他们的满意程度都比这 5 种小公司要低
In general, do smaller companies appear to have employees? So, I'm going to say, yes.
总的来说 小型公司的员工满意程度更高吗? 我的答案是 yes
And then, use the space above to assist in matching each variable A,
下一题 利用上面的空单元格来帮助解答
B, or C as the appropriate key.
在相应的陈述后 对应好正确的 a b c 选项
So, do individuals who program outside of work have higher job satisfaction?
在工作之外也编程的人 工作满意度更高吗?
Does flexibility to work outside of the office appear to have an influence?
工作地点的灵活性会对工作满意度有影响吗?
A friend says a doctoral degree increases the chance of having a job that you like.
有个朋友说 拥有博士学位的人更可能找到自己喜欢的工作
Does that seem true?
这是正确的吗?
So, there's a bunch of things tied to job satisfaction.
有很多因素都有工作满意度有关
And right now, we're individually looking at a lot of them.
我们其实有单独查看其中的一些因素
We're kind of just like drawing
提出一些潜在的假设
some potential hypotheses and finding descriptive statistics that relate to them,
利用相关的描述性统计学来进行探索
just to build hunches.
只是为了建立数据直觉
We probably want to do something more stringent to predict job satisfaction,
我们可能要做一些更严谨的探索才能预测工作满意度
if we want to have a better idea of what actually drives it.
如果想真正挖掘背后的规律的话
But we're getting some, at least,
但是现在利用描述性统计学知识
like descriptive evidence in some of these cases.
其实也能回答一些问题
So, do individuals who program outside of work?
先来找到那些工作之外也编程的人
I'm going to just leave that df.columns.
使用 df.columns
So, there's this ProgramHobby column,
有一个叫 ProgramHobby 的特征
I'm just going to drop that in here.
直接复制过来
Does the flexibility to work outside of the office appear to have an influence?
工作地点的灵活性会对满意度有影响吗?
I don't know what that's doing.
不知道这里是怎么了
It's taking a long time.
运行得很慢
There's this thing called HomeRemote.
有一个特征叫做 HomeRemote
I'm guessing that that might have to do with the second part.
我猜这个特征跟第二个问题相关
Yeah, so, it looks like the lowest job satisfaction
结果出来了 没有编程爱好的人工作满意度最低
doesn't program for a hobby and the highest job satisfaction of developers do.
而最高工作满意度的人则拥有编程这一爱好
So, it kind of makes sense that if you even do this for fun,
这其实是合理的 如果编程是你的兴趣爱好
you probably have at least a higher probability of liking what you do at work.
那至少有较大的概率会喜欢你在工作中的编程
So, I'm just going to say, they appear to have a higher job satisfaction.
所以我认为他们有更高的工作满意度
That does appear to be true.
结果应该是 a
Does flexibility to work outside the office appear to
工作地点更自由的人
have any sort of evidence to suggest higher job satisfaction?
是不是也更满意自己的工作呢?
So, these people work remote,
这些是远程工作的人
work remote, work remote, work remote.
这三个 全都是远程工作的
The lowest, substantially lowest, never work remotely.
满意度最低的则是那些从来没有远程工作过的人
But essentially, everyone else does.
基本上其他组都有远程工作过
So the very lowest group and an actually,
工作满意度最低的组
especially from the people who do it almost all the time
与几乎总是远程工作的组
have pretty high point value difference.
差距相当大
We could, again, try to do something to prove that that was
当然 这里也可以用一些
significant or not via like inferential methods.
推论统计的方法来判断这一差距是否显著
So, I'm going to say, that does appear to be true.
所以这个论述 我认为是正确的
Your friend says doctoral degrees increased.
下个论述中提到了 博士学位
So, this has to do with formal education.
那么就是跟教育程度 (FormalEducation) 有关
So, let's do that as well.
我们来看一下
So, I'll drop that in this part now.
把这个复制过来
Let's take a look at that.
看一下结果
Yeah, so the doctoral degree tends to be the highest and it looks like,
确实是 具有博士学位的人满意度最高
again, that's pretty substantial compared to the other groups.
并且跟其他群体相比 也拉开了差距
It's a full point two points higher especially compared
跟最低的只有学士学位的人相比
to those with just a Bachelor's degree, it's the lowest.
差距是比较大的
So, I'll say, that appears to be true as well.
所以 我认为这句表述也是正确的
So, all of those kind of appear to be true and it looks like that's what they found.
来看一下结果 回答正确